Guide to Crouse Health Institutional Repository
Crouse Health
Crouse Health Institutional Repository
1887 - 2015
Crouse Health Library manages a repository of historic materials documenting the history of Crouse Hospital and its precursors; Syracuse Hospital for Women & Children, Syracuse Memorial hospital, and Crouse-Irving Memorial Hospital and their affiliated nursing schools. Items in the collection include minutes, official publications, photographs, and artifacts spanning the period of the hospital’s founding in 1887 to the present.
81.62 linear feet
Crouse Hospital
Crouse Health 736 Irving Avenue Syracuse, NY 13210
The Crouse Health archival collection is housed on-site in the hospital library and can only be accessed by staff. Researchers are encouraged to contact the library at Library@crouse.org or (315) 470-7380 concerning any collection material they would like to access for their research so that arrangements can be made.
Crouse Hospital’s history begins in 1887 with the founding, by a group of community-minded women, of the Syracuse Women’s Hospital and Training School for Nurses. It was the only hospital in the area at the time attending to the specific healthcare needs of women and children; still a strategic focus today in fulfillment of the hospital’s mission to provide the best in patient care and to promote community health. In 1902 its name changed to Syracuse Hospital for Women and Children and by 1908 the hospital began to admit men. In 1918, the name was changed to Syracuse Memorial Hospital to reflect its broader range of services. In 1929, the hospital moved to its present location on Irving Avenue. In 1946, after World War II and the establishment of a cooperative arrangement with Syracuse University’s School of Nursing, the Syracuse Memorial Hospital School of Nursing was dissolved.
Crouse-Irving Hospital, destined to merge with Syracuse Memorial, was founded by a group of physicians and investors under the leadership of Dr. William L. Wallace in 1912. In 1913 Crouse-Irving Hospital School of Nursing was founded. For many years, Syracuse Memorial Hospital and Crouse-Irving Hospital operated separately while being located across the street from each other. The two hospitals merged in 1968 into Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital. Crouse-Irving’s School of Nursing became the Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital School of Nursing at that time. Following the merger, plans were begun to expand and modernize the existing facilities. As part of the S.H.A.R.E. campaign to modernize healthcare facilities in Onondaga County, funds were raised to replace the deteriorating Crouse-Irving Hospital Building. In 1976, the Irving Unit (attached to the Memorial Unit, the former Syracuse memorial Hospital) was opened while the former Crouse-Irving Hospital was converted to an educational building for the hospital the School of Nursing, then demolished in 1991 when the present Harry and Lillian Marley Education Center opened. In June 1996, a new name was announced, changing Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital to Crouse Hospital. In 2015 the Crouse Hospital School of Nursing was renamed the Bill and Sandra Pomeroy College of Nursing at Crouse Hospital.
The development of the hospital, its services to the Syracuse community, education of nurses and trends in healthcare delivery is documented in the archival collections housed in the Crouse Hospital Library.
Crouse Hospital
The collection consists of items transferred to Crouse Hospital Library and covers the period of the hospitals founding in 1887 to present day. After re-location to the Marley Education Center in the spring of 1991, all material related to the hospital was re-housed in acid-free materials during an archives organization project. Materials are arranged into the following series which as closely as possible reflects the document’s department of origin:
Annual Reports (1888-1999)
Administration (1892- 1993)
Artifacts (1895-1985)
Auxiliary, Harmony Circle, Other Affiliated Groups (1888-1992)
Board of Trustees including minutes, reports, and biographies of members (1887-1990)
Bulletins
Crouse Irving School of Nursing (1887-1999)
Department Papers (1958-2000)
Financial including audits (1913-1930)
Crouse Health Foundation including campaign literature (1926-1997)
General History (1887-1990) Includes commemorative publications and reprints
Other Publications (1930-1999)
Permits and Licenses (1913-1930)
Photographs (1984-1997)
Physician’s Papers (1899-1900)
Planning and Feasibility Studies for Facilities (1917)
Plaques (1966)
Scrapbooks (1925-1996)
- Annual Reports, 1888 - 1999
  Components arranged by format.
  - Published/Bound Annual Reports, 1888 - 1989; Published and bound Annual Reports from the Syracuse Hospital for Women and Children, Syracuse Memorial Hospital, and Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital.; Syracuse Hospital for Women and Children; Syracuse Memorial Hospital; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital; Bound Volumes
    Subcomponents arranged chronologically.
    - Annual Reports, 1888 - 1905; Syracuse Hospital for Women and Children
      Each report Includes hospital and nursing school administrative staff, the constitution, association members, bylaws, hospital charging system, annual reports of the secretary, treasurer, and superintendent, assets & liabilities, gifts and donations, nursing school graduates and state of the nursing school.
      See index located with the Annual Reports monograph 1888-1905 for tuberculosis info.
    - Annual Reports, 1907 - 1917; Syracuse Hospital for Women and Children
    - Annual Reports, 1918 - 1928; Syracuse Memorial Hospital
    - Annual Reports, 1929 - 1937; Syracuse Memorial Hospital
    - Annual Reports, 1938 - 1949; Syracuse Memorial Hospital
    - Annual Reports, 1975 - 1983; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital
    - Annual Reports, 1975 - 1989; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital
  - Published/Unbound Annual Reports, 1888 - 1999; The published and unbound Annual Reports of the Syracuse Hospital for Women and Children, Syracuse Memorial Hospital, Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital, and Crouse Hospital.; Syracuse Hospital for Women and Children; Syracuse Memorial Hospital; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital; Crouse Hospital (Box 0001, Box 0002, Box 0003, Box 0004)
    - Annual Reports, 1888 - 1916; Syracuse Hospital for Women and Children (Box 0001)
    - Annual Reports, 1919 - 1937; Syracuse Memorial Hospital (Box 0002)
    - Annual Reports, 1939 - 1986; Syracuse Memorial Hospital; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital (Box 0003)
    - Annual Reports, 1987 - 1999; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital; Crouse Hospital (Box 0004)
  - Unpublished/Unbound Annual Reports, 1942 - 1960; The Annual Reports of the Superintendent to the Board of Trustees of the Syracuse Memorial Hospital.; Syracuse Memorial Hospital; Superintendent of the Syracuse Memorial Hospital (Box 0005, Box 0006, Box 0007)
    - Annual Reports, 1942 - 1950 (Box 0005)
    - Annual Reports, 1951 - 1956 (Box 0006)
    - Annual Reports, 1957 - 1960 (Box 0007)
- Administration, 1892 - 1993
- Artifacts, 1895 - 1985
  - Physical artifacts from the Syracuse Hospital for Women & Children, Syracuse Memorial Hospital, Crouse-Irving Hospital, and Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital., 1895 - 1985; A variety of artifacts from the Syracuse Hospital for Women & Children, Syracuse Memorial Hospital, Crouse-Irving Hospital, and Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital.; Syracuse Hospital for Women and Children; Syracuse Memorial Hospital; Crouse-Irving Hospital; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital (Box 0115, Box 0116, Box 0117, Box 0118, Box 0119)
- Auxiliary/Harmony Circle/Other Affiliated Groups, 1888 - 1992
  - Publications, 1888 - 1994; Materials published by the Auxiliary/Harmony Circle/Other Affiliated Groups.; Harmony Circle; Syracuse Memorial Hospital Men's Association; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital Auxiliary (Box 0043)
    - Harmony Circle 1888-1938, Harmony Circle; Syracuse Memorial Hospital; Three copies.
    - The Clock Tower, 1976 - 1984; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital Auxiliary; Newsletter of the Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital Auxiliary.
    - Harmony Circle Clippings, Minutes, Ephemera, 1937; Harmony Circle; Syracuse Memorial Hospital
    - Syracuse Memorial Hospital Men's Association, 1947; Syracuse Memorial Hospital; Syracuse Memorial Hospital Men's Association
    - Auxiliary Invitation s, 1935 - 1973; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital; Harmony Circle; Syracuse Memorial Hospital; Crouse-Irving Women's Auxiliary
    - Harmony Circle Annual Reports, 1951 - 1954; Syracuse Memorial Hospital; Harmony Circle
    - Harmony Circle Newsletters, 1952 - 1972; Harmony Circle; Syracuse Memorial Hospital
    - Harmony Circle History, 1972; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital; Harmony Circle
    - Harmony Circle Brochure, 1968; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital; Harmony Circle
    - Harmony Circle PR, by-laws, memos, 1970 - 1971; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital; Harmony Circle
    - 7th Annual Lights of Love Lighting Ceremony Program, November 28, 1994; Crouse Irving Memorial Auxiliary; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital
    - Harmony Circle Cookbook, 1903; Syracuse Hospital for Women and Children; Harmony Circle
  - Auxiliary Scrapbooks, 1973 - 1981; Scrapbook created by the Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital Auxiliary.; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital (Box 0044)
  - Auxiliary Scapbook and Newsletters, 1958 - 1991; Scrapbook created by the Crouse-Irving Hospital Auxiliary and copies of the Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital Auxiliary's newsletter, The ClockTower.; Crouse-Irving Hospital; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital (Box 0045)
    - Scrapbook, 1958 - 1969; Crouse-Irving Hospital; Crouse-Irving Hospital Auxiliary
    - The ClockTower, 1975 - 1991; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital Auxiliary
  - Scrapbook, 1949 - 1969; Scrapbook created by the Syracuse Memorial Hospital Auxiliary.; Syracuse Memorial Hospital; Syracuse Memorial Hospital Auxiliary (Box 0083)
  - Scapbooks, 1919 - 1958; Scrapbooks created by the Crouse-Irving Hospital Auxiliary.; Crouse-Irving Hospital; Crouse-Irving Hospital Auxiliary (Box 0082)
  - Crouse-Irving Auxiliary History, 1967 - 1973; History of the Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital Auxiliary.; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital Auxiliary (Box 0084)
  - Harmony Circle/Auxiliary Minutes, 1911 - 1994; Minutes from the meeting of the Harmony Circle Auxiliary.; Syracuse Hospital for Women and Children; Syracuse Memorial Hospital; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital; Harmony Circle Auxiliary (Box 0046)
  - Auxiliary History, 1959 - 1992; Materials related to the history of the Crouse-Irving Hospital Auxiliary and the Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital Auxiliary.; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital; Crouse-Irving Hospital; Crouse-Irving Hospital Auxiliary; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital Auxiliary (Box 0047)
  - Unboxed Materials, 1913 - 1980; Unboxed materials associated with the Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital Auxiliary, the Syracuse Memorial Hospital Auxiliary, and the Crouse-Irving Hospital Auxiliary.; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital; Syracuse Memorial Hospital; Crouse-Irving Hospital; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital Auxiliary; Syracuse Memorial Hospital Auxiliary; Crouse-Irving Hospital Auxiliary
    - Oversized color photograph of members, 1980
    - Photograph of the Harmony Square/SMH Coffee Shop Donors, 1961
    - Crouse-Irving Hospital Auxiliary Minutes, 1913 - 1929
- Board of Trustees, 1887 - 1990
  - Quarterly and Annual Meetings, 1887 - 1906; Syracuse Hospital for Women and Children; Transcripts from the Syracuse Hospital for Women and Children Organization (Quarterly and Annual) Meetings. (Box 0063)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1947 - 1989; Minutes of Meetings for the Crouse-Irving Hospital Board of Trustees and the Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital Board of Trustees.; Crouse-Irving Hospital; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital (Box 0064)
  - Manual & Member List, 1887 - 1990; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital Board of Trustees Manuals and Syracuse Memorial Hospital Board of Trustees Member List.; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital; Syracuse Memorial Hospital (Box 0065)
    - Manual, 1989; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital
    - Manual, 1990; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital
    - Board of Trustees List, 1887 - 1964; Syracuse Memorial Hospital
  - Bound Volumes of Meeting Minutes, 1887 - 1988; Syracuse Hospital for Women and Children; Syracuse Memorial Hospital; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital; Crouse-Irving Hospital; Bound Volumes; Bound volumes of Meeting Minutes for the Syracuse Hospital for Women and Children, Syracuse Memorial Hospital, Crouse-Irving Hospital, and Crouse-Irving Memorial Hospital.
    - Syracuse Memorial Hospital Board of Trustee Minutes, 1887 - 1950; Syracuse Memorial Hospital
    - Executive Committee Minutes, 1951 - 1953; Crouse-Irving Hospital
    - Attendance Ledgers, 1953 - 1970; Syracuse Memorial Hospital
    - Executive Committee Minutes, 1965 - 1968
    - Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital Board Minutes, 1968 - 1978; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital
    - Joint Conference Committee 1979, Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital
    - Joint Conference Committee, 1980 - 1990; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital
    - Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital Board of Trustees Manual, 1989 - 1990; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital
    - Crouse-Irving Hospital Board of Trustees Minutes, 1913 - 1962; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital
    - Hospital Planning Joint Committee, 1963; Crouse-Irving Hospital
    - Board Staff, Alumni Auxiliary, 1961 - 1968; Crouse-Irving Hospital
    - Joint Conference Committee, 1973 - 1978; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital
    - Medical Staff Minutes, 1894 - 1977 (Box 1894-1956, Box 1957-1977)
      - Box 1894-1956, January 30, 1894 - November 6, 1919
    - Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital Medical Staff, 1967 - 1987; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital
    - Medical Staff Committee, 1973 - 1988; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital
- Bulletins, 1913 - 1994
  - Bound Crouse-Irving Hospital Bulletins, 1913 - 1967; Bound volumes of Crouse-Irving Hospital's Bulletins.; Crouse-Irving Hospital; Bound Volumes
    - Volume 1, 1913 - 1914
    - Volume 2, 1915
    - Volume 3, 1916
    - Volume 4, 1917
    - Volume 5, 1918
    - Volume[s] 6,7,8, 1918 - 1921
    - Volumes[s] 9,10,11, 1922 - 1924
    - Volume[s] 12,13,14, 1925 - 1927
    - Volume[s] 15,16,17, 1928 - 1930
    - Volume[s] 18,19,20, 1931 - 1933
    - Volume[s] 21,22,23, 1934 - 1936
    - Volume[s] 24,25,26, 1937 - 1939
    - Volume[s] 27,28,29,30,31, 1940 - 1944
    - Volume[s] 32,33,34,35,36,37,38,39,40, 1956 - 1961
    - Volume[s] 38,39,40,41,42, 1962 - 1967
  - Unbound Crouse-Irving Hospital Bulletins, 1922 - 1968; Unbound Crouse-Irving Hospital Bulletins.; Crouse-Irving Hospital (Box 0010, Box 0011)
    - Unbound Crouse-Irving Hospital Bulletins, 1922 - 1944 (Box 0010)
    - Unbound Crouse-Irving Hospital Bulletins, 1956 - 1968 (Box 0011)
  - Bound Syracuse Memorial Hospital Bulletins (The Clock Tower), 1956 - 1968; Bound copies of the Clock Tower, Syracuse Memorial Hospital's Bulletin.; Syracuse Memorial Hospital; Bound Volumes
    - Clock Tower, March 1956, vol.19:2
    - Clock Tower, 1962-1968
  - Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital (The Pulse), 1972 - 1994; Unbound copies of The Pulse, the Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital Bulletin.; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital (Box 0008, Box 0009)
    - The Pulse, 1972 - 1986 (Box 0008)
    - The Pulse, 1987 - 1994 (0009)
- Crouse-Irving School of Nursing, 1887 - 1999
- Department Papers, 1958 - 2000
- Financial, 1913 - 1930
  - Audits, 1913 - 1930; Hurdman & Cranstoun, CPAs; Audits: Syracuse Hospital for Women & Children and Syracuse Memorial Hospital & Community Chest. (Box 0066, Box 0067, Box 0068)
  - Financial Paperwork, 1913 - 1914; Crouse-Irving Hospital; Financial Paperwork for the Crouse-Irving Hospital. (Box 0069)
    - Profits & Losses, 1913 - 1914; Crouse-Irving Hospital
    - Bank Statements & Cancelled Checks, 1913 - 1914; Crouse-Irving Hospital
    - "The Work of C-I Hospital in the Community 1912-1926... History & Financial Report for 1926", brochures; Crouse-Irving Hospital
- Foundation, 1926 - 1997
  - Paper Ephemera, 1926 - 1999; Paper ephemera related to the Syracuse Memorial Hospital Foundation, Crouse-Irving Hospital Foundation, Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital Foundation, and Crouse Hospital Foundation.; Syracuse Memorial Hospital; Crouse-Irving Hospital; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital; Crouse Hospital (Box 0048)
    - Syracuse Memorial Hospital Campaign for $2,500,000, 1926; Syracuse Memorial Hospital
    - Campaign Scrapbook, 1926; Syracuse Memorial Hospital
    - The New Crouse-Irving Hospital Fund... Looking Forward, 1965; Crouse-Irving Hospital
    - Board Manual, 1989; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital
    - Foundations for the Future, 1995 - 1997; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital; Crouse Hospital
    - Report on Giving, 1993 - 1999; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital; Crouse Hospital
    - The History of the Crouse Irving Memorial Foundation 1974-1994, Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital
    - Stationary Samples, Unknown
    - Delivering the Future Together, 1998; Crouse Hospital
  - Event Programs, 1978 - 1993; Tribute Evening's event programs and materials.; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital (Box 0049)
    - 10th Anniversary [program], 1978
    - Tribute to Dr. Richard P. Schmidt & Dr. Lewis W. Bluemle, Jr. [program], 1979
    - Tribute to Margaret Northrup [program], 1980
    - Tribute Honoring out Ares's Higher Education Institutions, 1982
    - Tribute Honoring our Hospital's Auxiliary [program], 1983
    - Tribute Honoring Sister Patricia Ann Mulherin [program], 1984
    - Honoring our Nurses [program], 1986
    - Centennial Year Honoring our Medical Staff [program], 1987
    - Honoring Ronald N. Goddard [program], 1988
    - Honoring James H. Abbott [program, invitations, stationary], 1989
    - Honoring William A. Hiller [program/calendar], 1990
    - Honoring Hedwig Sulzle [program/calendar, guest list], 1991
    - Honoring Orletta S. Vadenboncoeur [program/calendar], 1992
    - Honoring David G. Murray [program, postcard], 1993
  - Event Programs, 1994 - 1997; Tribute Evening's event programs and materials.; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital (Box 0050, Box 0050a)
    - Honoring Central New York Community Foundation [program, table assignments, newspaper], 1994
    - Honoring James Maher [program], 1995
    - Honoring Kenneth A. Shaw [program], 1996
    - Honoring Ernest Sarason, MD [program], 1997
    - Honoring Harold H. Wanamaker, MD [program, invitation], 1998
    - Misc. Publications, 2000
  - Foundation Documents, 1984 - 1997; Documents related to the Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital Foundation and the Crouse Hospital Foundation.; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital; Crouse Hospital (Box 0051)
    - A Special Newsletter for the Alumnae Association of Syracuse Memorial Hospital, 1996; Syracuse Memorial Hospital
    - The New Crouse Irving Memorial Medical Equipment Fund, 1984; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital
    - Dialogue: A Conversation with our Constitutents, 1996 - 1997; Crouse Hospital
- History, general, 1887 - 1990
  - History, Box 1, 1887 - 1987; Two copies of "Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital 1887-1987- 100 Years of Caring," one bound and one unbound.; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital (Box 0016)
    - Unbound manuscript, 1887 - 1987
    - Bound manuscript, 1887 - 1987; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital; Bound Volume
  - History, Box 2, 1887 - 1975; Collection of paper ephemera.; Syracuse Memorial Hospital; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital; Syracuse Hospital for Women and Children (Box 0015)
    - History of Syracuse Memorial Hospital and School of Nursing, 1930; Curnalia, Marjorie; Syracuse Memorial Hospital
    - Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital Chronology, 1991; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital
    - Newspaper clippings, 1929; Various newspaper clippings about the completion of the Syracuse Memorial Hospital.
    - "Memorial Hospital- Medical Center Unit -Is Dedicated", 1929; Article printed in the Syracuse University Alumni News.; Syracuse University Alumni Association
    - Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital Mission Statement, 1975; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital
    - "Two Mission Hours of Service", 1962; Syracuse Memorial Hospital; brochures
    - Syracuse Memorial Hospital brochure, 1962; Brochure; Syracuse Memorial Hospital
    - "Hymn to Crouse Irving, Unknown; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital
    - Packet of Various Histories, 1937 - 1973; Crouse-Irving Hospital; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital; Packet accumulated by the Communications Department.
    - Hospital Growth, 1938; Chart that illustrates hospital growth.
    - List of Medical Staff, Board of Trustees, and Items Laid in Cornerstone, 1887; Badly burned.; Syracuse Hospital for Women and Children
  - History, Box 3, 1926 - 1982; Promotional printed materials.; Syracuse Herald American Empire Magazine; Empire Magazine; Syracuse Memorial Hospital (Box 0019)
    - "A Day in the Life of a Hospital", 1982; Empire Magazine; Promotional material published by Empire Magazine about Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital.
    - "Names That Will Live", 1926; Syracuse Memorial Hospital; Promotional printed material created by the Syracuse Memorial Hospital.
    - "Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital's New Addition", 1976; Promotional material printed by the Syracuse Herald American Empire Magazine about Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital.; Syracuse Herald American Empire Magazine
  - History, Box 4, 1887 - 1987; Collection of paper ephemera.; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital; The Syracuse Hearld Journal; John Russell Pope & Dwight James Daum, Architects; Syracuse University; Syracuse Post; Syracuse Memorial Hospital; Syracuse Journal (Box 0093)
    - Touching Lives for a Hundred Years, 1887 - 1987; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital; Centennial calendar.
    - "Your Hospital... The Story of a Revolution", 1952; Article reprinted from The Syracuse Hearld-Journal, Hearld American.; The Syracuse Hearld Journal; Covert, Cathy
    - Architectural Drawing, 1926; Architectural drawing of the City Hospital, Medical School, Memorial Hospital.; John Russell Pope & Dwight James Daum, Architects
    - Property Maps- Irving Avenue, 1923; Mounted on form core.; Syracuse University
    - "An Honor to the City- New Home of the Women's and Children's Hospital... History of the Institution During a Period of Eight Years", 1895; Full description of the Syracuse Hospital for Women and Children's new building.; Syracuse Post
    - "Corner Stone Laid", 1895; Mounted.; Syracuse Post
    - "The New Syracuse Memorial Hospital", 1929; Syracuse Post
    - "Women Active in the Creation of the New Syracuse Memorial Hospital", 1929; Syracuse Memorial Hospital
    - "Hospital Certain, Raise $2,331,327", 1926; Syracuse Journal
  - History, Box 5, 1926 - 1999; Copperplates used for publications.; Syracuse Memorial Hospital; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital (0017)
    - Nurses in the Service, 1999; Copperplates.; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital
    - Names that will Live, 1926; Copperplates.; Syracuse Memorial Hospital
- Other Publications, 1930 - 1999
  - Other Publications, Box 1, 1930 - 1998; Publications from the Crouse-Irving Hospital, Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital, and Crouse Hospital. (For publications produced by departments, see name for department.); Crouse-Irving Hospital; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital; Crouse Hospital (Box 0013)
    - Issues and Answers: A Summary of and Response to Topics Raised at the Monthly Employee Forum, 1984 - 1986; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital
    - Scoop & Scope, 1972 - 1974; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital
    - Behind the Scenes (unbound), 1975 - 1988; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital
    - Behind the Scenes (bound), 1976 - 1991; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital
    - The Medical Dialogue, 1977; Crouse Irving Memorial Hospital